the code we've been given in this
problem
contains nested loops we have an outer
loop defined on lines one through
seven and an inner loop on lines four
through
six you can see that currently
both of these loops are infinite loops
there is no reserved word break
in either of these loops and they will
just continue to iterate infinitely
as you can see if we just run the code
as it is we'll be stuck in the inner
loop
so the first thing that we can do here
is to
break out of the inner loop at the
appropriate time
we want to output the string this
is the inner loop one time prior to
exiting the block
so we can place break on line
six after we output the appropriate
string
and expect to exit this inner loop
the infinite loop we're currently stuck
in is the outer loop you can see that
this is the inner loop we'll print only
one time
the problem here is that the outer loop
continues to
iterate which puts us back into the
inner loop
so now we need to figure out when is the
appropriate time to break out of this
outer loop if we place our break
statement in the outer loop
after we output this is the outer loop
our code's not going to run as expected
you can see that we skipped the inner
loop completely
[Music]
because these are nested loops we have
to be conscious not to break out of the
outer loop
prior to actually entering the inner
loop
[Music]
so we can move our break statement for
the outer loop
down to line nine now we will only be
breaking out of the outer loop after
we've iterated through the inner loop
at this point we expect ruby to enter
the outer loop
and output the string this is the outer
loop
i'll put the string this is the inner
loop break out of the inner loop
and finally break out of the outer loop
on line nine
after exiting the outer loop ruby will
continue down to line 12
and output the string this is outside
all loops
so let's run our code and we're seeing
the expected output
you